(Respect copyright)
♪Memories hold you back
from fulfilling your dreams♪
♪Only by moving forward
can you find reunion♪
♪Endings only mark new routes♪
♪It's all part of the scenery♪
♪To the horizon's call♪
♪Your journey hasn't started♪
♪Towards mountains,
chase the stars bright♪
♪Let time embrace you
and wash away the past♪
♪Put every twist behind you♪
♪Drift leisurely through time♪
♪Make headway against the wind♪
♪Let mountains bow to your pace♪
♪Rush towards a life without regret♪
♪Let your nature burst free♪
=The First Jasmine=
=Episode 19=
Have you heard the news?
Yes.
I heard Prince Ding was investigating
the Yuan Fang case.
When the trail pointed
to the Eastern Palace,
Mo Jingli set himself on fire.
What do you think?
Eight years ago,
the Eastern Palace pressed you hard,
attempting to get you killed.
If not for your immense fortune,
there would be no peace today.
You showed benevolence,
leaving their child alive
and titling him as a prince.
Yet Mo Jingli harbored an ill ambition.
He failed to appreciate your grace,
even plotted secretly
and committed such a rebellious act.
Such a source of disaster
must be eradicated completely.
Lest it'll endanger the nation.
Both of your share similar opinions.
What do you think?
You shall be the one to decide.
Then investigate.
Marquis Muyang, order
the Imperial Court of Judicial Review
to guard all city gates
and key roads between wards.
Execute any suspicious person.
Everything related to
Mo Jingli and Eastern Palace,
be it a letter, document, or witness,
shall be captured.
The Left and Right Gate Guards
strictly guard all palace entrances.
No entry or exit is allowed
without my order.
Yes.
Back then, I told her not to keep
anyone of the Eastern Palace alive,
but she insisted on
showing her benevolence.
Can benevolence conquer the nation?
Benevolence can rule the nation.
Marquis Muyang,
if you don't change your mindset,
you will betray her one day.
Perhaps the only one
who truly understands her thoughts
in this world is me.
Do you think that fire
in the Eastern Palace
started on its own?
The matter is done.
Are all traces thoroughly erased?
It's merely an accident.
Your Majesty, Rest assured.
However, this case will be handled
by Imperial Court of Judicial Review.
If you wish to eradicate them,
the post of Chief Minister
of Imperial Court of Judicial Review...
Naturally, you'll be
the one to take on this post.
After eliminating the Eastern Palace,
it's only a matter of time
for you to reign the nation.
Even though she's now
the Empress Dowager,
whether she approves
of my methods or not,
only I can deliver the result she wants.
Every step on the road to power
is tainted by blood.
(Imperial Court of Judicial Review)
Guards, heed my command!
Everyone implicated in Mo Jingli
and the Eastern Palace
shall be captured.
Better to detain everyone
than to let any go.
Execute anyone who resist.
- Yes!
Don't move!
Be careful!
What's going on?
That serious?
This way! Hurry!
Go away.
How dare you trespass in here?
Let go of me!
Which office do you belong to?
We act by the imperial decree.
Move!
Hurry!
You go that way.
Get up!
What's wrong?
Move!
Let me go!
(Prince Li's Mansion)
Listen carefully.
From now on, this is under the rule
of Imperial Court of Judicial Review!
Go!
Yes!
Spread out.
Your Highness, many guards
from Imperial Court of Judicial Review
surrounded the entire mansion.
What right do you have to arrest me?
Move!
Let me go!
Don't touch me!
- Move!
- I'm innocent!
Move!
Hurry!
I'm innocent!
Anyone caught whispering
will also be detained.
Still thinking about Prince Li?
The Prince Li's mansion
has been inspected inside and out.
The fire spread fast.
Multiple crucial points were ignited.
There were many incendiary materials.
It shouldn't be a whim
but a premeditated plan.
He probably knew
his schemes were about to be exposed,
so he did it deliberately.
The Eastern Palace got overturned.
As the only descendant
of the late Crown Prince,
he's destined to die.
He even survived
such desperate circumstances.
Now, the case remains unresolved.
It is far from a hopeless dead end.
How could he set himself on fire?
That's just not him.
Li, if something's on your mind,
you can tell me.
I'm alright.
Do your legs hurt
from all the moving around lately?
No.
I had Qingyu prepare
salt packs for warm compress.
Qingyu, are they ready?
Yes, Your Highness.
Bring them here.
Your legs just healed.
You mustn't catch a cold.
I added mugwort leaves
to the salt packs,
perfect for warm compress.
Don't think that just because you
can stand and walk now,
then you're fully healed
and have no restrictions.
Even now, you shouldn't
stand for too long,
run fast, or fight anyone.
Yao.
Consider it for me
and for Prince Ding's Mansion.
Sister-in-law, Wuyou, and I,
we all count on you.
Does that feel better?
Much better.
You must be exhausted.
Don't worry about me anymore.
Get some rest today, okay?
(Jingzhao Prefecture)
Halt!
Your Highness!
You are finally back.
Something terrible has happened!
What?
Prince Ding, are you here
to get involved in it?
Such poor timing.
I act by the Empress Dowager's decree.
Anyone connected to Mo Jingli
or any guilty officials
from the Eastern Palace,
shall receive a thorough investigation.
I've told you many times.
I have no connection
to the Eastern Palace!
Shut it! How dare you deny?
Your Fourth Uncle
was a worker bought
by the Eastern Palace back then.
Coming and going daily,
who knows who he interacted with
or what business he handled for them.
And you
just happened to be present
at the ambush scene in Penglai Alley.
Now that Mo Jingli committed suicide
out of fear of punishment,
so the lead is cut.
I have every reason to suspect you
to be deeply involved in this case.
As the Military Secretary,
I went to Penglai Alley on duty!
What a Military Secretary!
Don't fret.
At the Imperial Court
of Judicial Review,
I will hear your excuses carefully.
Prince Ding, any objection
to my words?
Or, any objection
to Her Majesty's decree?
Her Majesty sent you
to investigate the case,
not to randomly slander
and frame decent men.
Decent men?
Whether he's a decent man,
it's not up to you.
We'll know after my investigation.
Mo Jingli
seemed so decent before.
He was so respectful
to the Empress Dowager
and the Emperor,
not a single fault found.
Now his schemes are exposed,
only then did I realize
that he had long harmed ill intentions,
playing the fool all along.
Her Majesty is benevolent.
But I know well
that to eliminate evil thoroughly,
we must eradicate it at its root.
Some things left alive
will eventually become disasters.
After I finish my investigation,
I'll give you an explanation.
Take him away.
Yes!
Deputy Prefect Zheng,
come with me.
Yes!
Shut the door.
You...
What?
Do you really think I fear you?
Have you forgotten that?
I once fought in fierce battlefields
and killed more men than you knew.
You fear Marquis Muyang, but not me?
You're using illegal punishment.
How dare you treat me this way?
I'll impeach you to the Empress Dowager.
Talk law with me?
Give me the law book.
Open your eyes and read it carefully.
Any one of these laws could convict you.
You useless parasite!
Abusing the power
of Jingzhao Prefecture,
you've done many dirty schemes
all these years.
Think you can hide them?
Believe me or not,
even if I kill you today,
no one would dare speak for you.
Were you present
during Qiu Xian's interrogation?
You told Marquis Muyang
about everything?
I know your every move.
I spared you
just to see what you're up to.
But now,
you're useless.
Your Highness.
As colleagues, we share life and death.
If Wang Suwu dies,
you won't live either.
Your Highness!
Your Highness, spare me!
I won't do it again.
Take him away!
Your Highness, spare me!
No! Your Highness, I won't do it again.
Your Highness!
(Jingzhao Prefecture)
Your Highness.
Marquis Muyang captured Wang Suwu
to make an example of him.
We can't just sit back.
We need to rescue Wang Suwu.
And we need to get rid
of Zheng Zuoshi,
that traitor.
Rest assured.
We have planted agents in
the Imperial Court of Judicial Review.
I've already sent word,
ordering them
to keep an eye on Wang Suwu.
Report any trouble immediately.
One more thing.
You go investigate
the Prince Li's Mansion again,
including nearby places like Jvde Tower,
Dehua Ward, Banruo Temple,
Taiping Ward, and other areas.
Check if there's any hidden passage
or canal connecting to the mansion.
But we already found
Prince Li's remains in the ruins, right?
The remains' features
were too damaged to recognize.
Not solid proof.
We must find him,
alive or dead.
The Prince Li case is now handled
by Imperial Court of Judicial Review.
It's hard for us to interfere.
Your Highness.
Your Highness, urgent news
from Prince Li's Mansion.
Princess Li committed suicide.
Princess Li was already heartbroken
over Prince Li's death.
Out of grief, she tried to kill herself.
Fortunately, a servant
found her and saved her.
Marquis Muyang, you want
to take her for interrogation now.
Do you aim to kill her?
How is Princess Li?
Marquis Muyang,
luckily, she was found in time.
Her life is not in immediate danger.
She only needs proper rest.
Her Majesty's decree
only said to seal the mansion
and arrest remnants.
Did it mention imprisoning Princess Li?
Prince Li plotted treason.
How can his family escape implication?
I don't escape implication.
I want to join him in death.
Marquis Muyang, I know
you're ordered to investigate officials
to investigate the case.
But so far,
I think you haven't secured
one confession or a letter as evidence.
What now? You want to drive
a princess consort to her death?
It's the Empress Dowager herself
who bestowed this marriage.
Your Highness, what do you mean?
You cannot take her.
If I leave her and trouble occurs...
If trouble occurs,
I will personally enter the palace
and apologize to the Empress Dowager.
Fine.
Let's go.
Did you see his remains yesterday?
The night when the edict
of marriage was issued,
I was too happy to sleep.
I ran into the courtyard
to count the stars
and told myself,
the number of stars I counted
would be the number of years
I'd be with Prince Li.
I counted over a hundred.
I was so happy
that I could grow old with him.
But we married only half a year ago.
Only about a hundred days.
So every single star
could only count for one day.
If I'd known it,
I would've counted until dawn.
You once asked me.
Before my marriage,
I hadn't met Your Highness much.
What do I like about him?
But love doesn't have to bloom
from meeting someone in person, right?
I read his poems.
I heard the music he composed.
Within his words and music,
I already came to know him.
And I know so much about him.
Because of all these small things,
he came to occupy a place in my heart.
Isn't that okay?
Can't one just love someone one-sided?
Is one-sided love deemed worthless?
I'd do anything for him.
I truly
used all my strength to love him.
Actually, I should have hated you.
You're arrogant and domineering.
Your mother is greedy and shortsighted.
Though what happened to me
doesn't relate to you two,
I should have hated you.
Do you understand?
But I don't hate you.
Because you're so naive.
I can't resent a fool.
But even a fool like you,
is too good for that Mo Jingli.
Loving someone is a wonderful thing.
But you can't just devote yourself in it
without knowing anything.
Mo Jingli is the son
of the late Crown Prince.
He's the descendant
of the Eastern Palace.
That means, he might
set a raging fire at any moment,
burning himself
and everything around him to ashes.
Ye Ying, you said you love him.
But when he set that fire,
did he think of you?
When we were young,
we both studied the Zhuangzi.
There was a saying in it,
"Those with deep cravings
have shallow understanding."
Remember it?
I need to ask you one thing.
Go ahead.
That night,
when His Highness sent me away,
he said something strange to me.
What did he say?
He said,
"I'm sorry I failed you."
"So be obedient and go."
"If fate permits,"
"we may meet again someday."
Ye Li, you're smart.
Figure this out for me.
Does what he said indicate
that he might still be alive?
Mo Xiuyao said
he and Marquis Muyang reached
Prince Li's mansion at the same time.
(Prince Li's Mansion)
Then guards sealed off the mansion.
The fire spread fast.
There were many incendiary materials.
So Mo Jingli couldn't escape from fire.
Li, how is Princess Li?
She's fine now.
I thought you two are at odds.
Indeed.
But she is still my sister.
After all,
neither she nor her mother
has ever done anything truly heinous.
Then let's go back.
Let's go.
Okay.
(Marquis Muyang's Mansion)
Father!
What are you doing?
Take a look. Something wonderful.
This thing's called
- coconut.
- Coconut.
Father, you know this?
I used to drink this
frequently in Lingnan.
Father, listen to me.
This coconut isn't like
the ones from Lingnan.
It came across the ocean
from South Seas.
There are few even in the capital.
Here, try it.
No. It's too sweet for me.
They say this relieves
summer heat, not sweet at all.
Come on, try it.
You drink it.
Just try it. Try it.
Fine, just a little.
Okay.
How is it? Delicious?
Look at this top.
Put it on the head.
Does it look like a black gauze cap?
(Lakeview Garden)
Marquis Muyang.
Alright.
I heard you've been
looking for manors recently.
Found any?
Haven't found the right one just yet.
Then don't look for it.
Plenty of empty rooms in here.
Just pick one.
This room is quite nice.
You can live in this room.
Just settle down.
So you can
chat and talk with me.
Thanks, Marquis Muyang.
Here. Let me show you something good.
This is
called Coconut.
Tianyang brought it back.
I've tried it before.
Too sweet for my taste.
I thought you young folks might like it.
So I brought it to you.
I've already opened it for you.
Try it.
Young Lord gave this to you.
I think it's improper.
It's just food.
Don't mind that much.
Here, take it.
Take it.
Thank you.
Try it.
Come on.
I almost forgot.
Tianyang said to use this bamboo straw
to suck out the juice inside.
Take it.
Try it.
Go on.
Yes.
How's it?
It's sweet.
I knew you young folks would like it.
Tianyang said this thing
looks like a black gauze cap.
To me, it looks more like a flowerpot.
Perfect for planting flowers.
What do you think?
Drink it.
Look, it's all over you.
Yes.
(Someone like Mo Jingli,)
(vindictive, valuing life above all,)
(before reaching his dead end,)
(he wouldn't kill himself.)
(He probably escaped using the fire.)
(Record of Huai River Dredging)
I've found all the things you wanted.
I even dug out the items
at the bottom of the storage for you.
Here's the Chronicle
of Yongzhou Prefecture.
This is the Record
of Huai River Dredging.
And this,
Capital Underground Waterways Map.
And this one.
I heard it's from
the reign of Emperor Taizu,
(Dehua Ward Development Map)
the original survey map
from the capital's reconstruction.
This is a treasure.
Look at you.
You studied celestial phenomena
a while ago,
and now underground waterways maps?
What exactly are you up to?
I have my reasons.
Fine. I'll leave them to you.
I have work to do.
The capital has a total of 108 wards.
Wards and markets connect,
and streets crisscross.
They excavated
the Longshou, Qingming, and Yong'an
canals as the backbone,
with branch canals forming a net,
densely spread underneath
(West Market, East Market, Dehua Ward)
West Market, East Market, Dehua Ward,
(Renshou Ward, Chongren Ward)
Renshou Ward,
(Xianzhu Ward)
and Chongren Ward.
(Prince Li's Mansion
directly faces Dehua Ward.)
(Mo Jingli only needs to dig
a secret passage from his mansion)
(to the underground canal
beneath Dehua Ward,)
(then leaves via that canal.)
(To its west flows a small river.)
(There must be an underground canal exit
nearby leading to the river.)
(Perhaps he'll take that route.)
(Dehua Ward)
Dehua Ward.
Why are you following me?
You saved my life once before,
then I almost got you killed.
All in all, I owe you two lives.
If I don't repay you, this unsettles me,
and we can't be even.
No need. Stop following me.
Your Highness, the Imperial Court
of Judicial Review sent the person back.
Your Highness.
Don't move.
Rest assured.
I won't die that easily.
Send him home.
Find Physician Guan to treat him.
- Yes!
That traitor Zhou Jing!
What about Prince Li's Mansion?
Still impossible to investigate?
It's quite tightly guarded.
Our people got driven away
by guards under the pretext
of protecting the scene.
(Capital Underground Waterways Map)
(That night,
when His Highness sent me away,)
(he said something strange to me.)
"If fate permits,"
"we may meet again someday."
Ye Li, you're smart.
Figure this out for me.
Does what he said indicate
that he might still be alive?
Your Highness, a message from Prince Ding.
He said due to
heavy official duties tonight,
he won't return to the mansion.
Understood.
Yes.
Come out.
You've followed me this far,
aren't you going to lend a hand?
Weren't you saying you owe me lives?
You want me to kill all of them?
Come with me.
We enter from here.
For height like this, no problem.
I can enter without this.
I need it.
Neither do you.
It's pitch-black in here.
What are you looking for?
Quiet!
(The key to the hydraulic mechanism
lies in leveraging the power of water)
(to maintain the balance.)
Looking for a secret passage?
That's my thing.
For hidden mechanisms or passages,
the most crucial thing
is to first find its...
Go fetch a bucket of water.
Water?
Go, hurry.
Pour it in
slowly, at a steady pace.
Where is this place?
The capital's underground waterways.
Based on the Water Control Records
from the Ministry of Works,
these were built
during the previous dynasty,
to drain the flooding in the capital,
and to bring living water
into the palace.
It cost quite a fortune
and took decades to complete.
This way.
There are several passages here.
Which one do we take?
There must be place names here.
Look for them.
(Jvde Tower)
Jvde Tower?
(Dehua Ward)
Underground canal in the southwest
(Prince Li's mansion)
starts from Prince Li's mansion
(Jvde Tower, Wuwei Zhai)
via Jvde Tower, Wuwei Zhai,
straight to the transport dock.
(Transport Dock)
The middle passage
is the main flood drainage canal,
(Dehua Ward, Ziyun Ward)
via Dehua Ward, Ziyun Ward,
connecting to the Yongding River.
Ye Li.
That way leads to the transport dock.
The West Market water inlet
diverges from the river.
It's highly populated and hard to hide.
The passage to the imperial city
is heavily guarded.
If he wanted
to leave the capital unnoticed,
he'd only take this passage,
the main flood drainage canal
leading to the outskirts.
I know who you're looking for.
You're looking for Mo Jingli.
No need to hide it from me.
I've figured it out.
A fire broke out
at the Prince Li's Mansion,
burning Prince Li
and several of his close aides.
But now it seems he didn't die.
Not bad. You could figure that out.
It's nothing.
For a top assassin,
combing through subtle clues,
and exposing the truth,
is a basic requisite.
Rest assured.
I have my own rules.
As an assassin, I stick
to the unbreakable rule,
which is to keep secrets
for the employers.
I'd swallow this secret,
never spread a word about it.
Do you belong
to some assassin organization?
Or are you a lone swordsman?
I can't tell you that.
Your last attempt on my life
was your first assassination mission,
wasn't it?
How did you know?
Seems we share quite the connection.
Well, when this is over,
if you need help, find me.
Considering our connection,
I can give you a discount.
(Iron)
Be careful.
Lots of people.
Go!
(Preview)
Your Highness.
The person ahead seems
to be Princess Ding.
Princess Ding interfered with
Imperial Court of Judicial Review affairs.
We await the discerning judgement
of you both, Your Majesties.
We fought with our lives
to secure the situation we have today.
You saw Master Zhu again?
He must be living in the capital.
But I've searched
every corner of the city,
and found no trace of him.
♪Memories hold you back
from fulfilling your dreams♪
♪Only by moving forward
can you find reunion♪
♪Endings only mark new routes♪
♪It's all part of the scenery♪
♪To the horizon's call♪
♪Your journey hasn't started♪
♪Towards mountains,
chase the stars bright♪
♪Both joy and grief
make the trip worthwhile♪
♪Trying to catch up
to your own lost shadow♪
♪Within the wilds, echoes thrive♪
♪Clear mind leads to a clear path♪
♪Be grateful to your losses♪
♪Make your steps weightless♪
♪Towards mountains,
chase the stars bright♪
♪Let time embrace you
and wash away the past♪
♪Put every twist behind you,
drift leisurely through time♪
♪Make headway against the wind,
let mountains bow to your pace♪
♪Rush towards a life without regret♪
♪Let your nature burst free♪
♪Unbound by form♪